Nathaniel Magee

nmagee@unb.ca • (506) 232-2842 • LinkedIn

Software Engineer with 3 years of experience in software development. I have worked on several aspects of the development stack including back-end development, database design, cloud infrastructure deployment, and user interface development. I am a dedicated and enthusiastic developer who is eager to learn about and create new technologies.

Experience

2018 - Present Software Engineer, Akiri

Currently working at Akiri as a Software Engineer developing a cloud-based platform to improve data liquidity in healthcare. The Akiri platform allows users to manage, monitor, and audit the exchange of medical data and securely share it using VPN technologies.

- Designed a system for processing and mass exporting of application audit logs for customer HIPAA compliance reviews.
- Aided in the development of the user interface using Vue and Vuetify.
- Investigated and implemented tools to improve the deployment of infrastructure in development and production environments. This included using tools such as Apex and Terraform to deploy Lambda, SQS, DynamoDB, Kinesis, and S3 resources.
- Created integration and unit tests using JUnit, MockK, Cypress, and PyTest.
- Developed back-end services using Java and Kotlin with Eclipse Vert.X

2016 - 2017 Software Developer, Fiddlehead Technology

Worked as a Software Developer at Fiddlehead Technology aiding in the development and support of Forecast Guardian, a tool designed to help with forecasting and demand planning for food and beverage manufacturers. Using statistical analysis Forecast Guardian would provide insight into demand trends and help identify issues and errors in the current forecasting methodologies.

- Aided in the redesign of the company's relational database and migration from MySQL to Postgres.
- Designed tools for processing customer data, identifying anomalies, and inserting the cleansed data for analysis.
- Designed a prototype web crawler to gather grocer flyer and sale information to help with producing more accurate forecasts.
- Developed back-end services using Java, Dropwizard, and Hibernate.
- Created unit tests using JUnit and Selenium.

Education

2013 - 2018 Bachelor's in Computer Science, University of New Brunswick

- Participated in the Co-Operative Education Program
- Graduated First Division



Programming Languages

Java, Kotlin, Python, JavaScript, SQL (MySQL, PSQL), Bash

Web Technologies

Vue, Vuetify, REST, JSON, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, JQuery

Developer Tools

GIT, Vim, IntelliJ, Eclipse, VSCode, GitHub, JIRA, Bitbucket, VirtualBox

Build Tools

Gradle, Maven, Jenkins

Cloud Platforms and Technologies

AWS, Docker, Terraform

Operating Systems:

Linux, MacOS, Windows

Interests

Computer Hardware

Over the years I have developed a keen interest in computer hardware and building computers. Currently I have built two gaming computers and a home server for myself as well as putting together parts list for several friends and relatives. I enjoy keeping up with the latest developments in computer hardware and gaming technologies.

Software and Programming

In my spare time I manage a personal server for myself as well as my close friends and family. This server is currently hosting an application called NextCloud which acts as an alternative to Google Drive which I use to store all of my files and photos.

Exercise and Sports

I am an avid athlete having played several sports including Basketball, Rugby, and Soccer. In my spare time I enjoy jogging, lifting weights, cycling, and downhill skiing.